

SKILLS

FRONTEND

JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Redux, HTML/CSS, Material-UI, **Bootstrap**

BACKEND Python, Django, C# .NET, Node.js

MOBILE

Ionic Angular, React Native

PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB

DATABASES

DEVOPS Bash scripting, Github, Azure,

Heroku, Netlify, Fundamentals of

Software Testing **OTHER** Linux, Agile, Confluence, Jira,

Figma, MS Office, MS PowerApps,

Audio and Video production

BASIC KNOWLEDGE Java, Scala, PHP, Kotlin, C, C++

LANGUAGES

English - Native Finnish - Novice Swedish - Novice

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

Kiuas Startup Accelerator Program, Spring 2024

Miimit Koodaa Ultrahack Hackathon, December 2023

Bash Scripting, Udemy September 2023

Certified Fullstack Developer, Integrify Academy April 2023

Nokia Hackathon, Laurea UAS October 2022

Google Analytics for Beginners October 2022

Inbound Marketing, Hubspot

Certificate of Completion, AMKoodari 2020

August 2021

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

KIMBERLY RUOHIO

Helsinki, Finland

I am a developer who has a background in music, theatre, and developmental editing. I am currently completing my BIT degree at Laurea, with only work study credits remaining. I am also participating in the Kiuas Startup program with Freely Energy Oy, where I am honing my skills with an entrepreneurial mindset of getting things done. Switching career paths is always challenging, but I enjoy the lifelong learning process of software development, always learning new skills and getting excited and making things. I am looking for roles where getting excited and making things is encouraged. I want to be part of making things people want to use.

RECENT PROJECTS

eLibrary | Full Stack project

React Redux, Typescript, C# ASP.NET EF, PostgreSQL

This project represents the culmination of everything I learned in Integrify's Fullstack program. The backend was built with #C ASP.NET Entity Framework with PostgreSQL database. The frontend is structured using React Redux with Typescript to create a just-about fully-functioning online Library. It features an interface that should feel familiar, allowing the user to browse books by author, categories, and publisher. Users can check their loan history, and edit their profiles, but the bulk of library features are on the admin side. The site features a side container admin panel, only available to authorized users, with full CRUD functionality, as well as processing loans and returns. The most exciting part was thinking about the admin usage, to make all the features easily reachable.

Digital Living Lab Booking Project

MS PowerApps

The Digital Living Lab Booking app facilitates browsing and checking out items from Laurea's Digital Living Lab. Admins can maintain loans and item availability with a simple and clean interface, while users can track checkout items, and be informed when items become available. This was a group project where my role as main developer with coding experience was to build and implement the app itself.

MovieDB | Mobile Frontend project React Native, Node.js, Expo

The MovieDB App was a group project, allowing the user to browse trending movies, as well as search for films, and TV shows, with the ability to tap through for more information on each result. The user can register, login and logout, as well as reset the username and password. It features a simple MySQL database to demonstrate user login, with hashed passwords. The keyboard type should also change depending on the type of text entry, and can be dismissed by tapping outside the text area throughout the application. My responsibility in the group was the UX/UI - the styling, implementing dark and light modes, keyboard functionality, as well as some help troubleshooting the database.

EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Freely Energy Oy | Helsinki | January 2024 - current

- · Responsible for the company's codebase and documentation, leveraging Test-Driven Development (TDD) and agile methodologies. Implemented the design and execution of comprehensive product testing frameworks for numerous APIs, facilitating seamless communication with hardware devices, using Python, and frontend frameworks as appropriate.
- · Actively participated in the Kiuas startup accelerator program, refining entrepreneurial acumen and accelerating business growth trajectory.
- · Elevated software development initiatives within a dynamic startup environment, driving technological innovation while fostering strategic partnerships and amplifying market presence.

FULLSTACK TRAINEE

Integrify | Helsinki | November 2022 - September 2023

- · Developed frontend, backend, and fullstack projects using HTML/CSS, React Redux, JavaScript, TypeScript, C# ASP.NET EF Core, and PostgreSQL
- Deployed projects using Azure, and developed bash scripting automations

DEVELOPMENTAL EDITOR

Freelance | Remote, Online | 2011 - November 2022

- Assisted authors in developing stories, developing characters, plots, and central themes of the books, as well the first wrangler of errant punctuation and grammar.
- · Authors edited maintain a reader rating on Goodreads of 4 stars and above. Won various awards, such as at the annual New Apple Literary Awards 2018.

ACTOR

Edita Publishing Oy | Helsinki, Finland | 2010 - 2010

English", and "Win-Win: English for your business career", demonstrating the proper use of English in a business environment.

• Performed VoiceOver work, and improvisation in front of the camera for "Engineering your

Freelance | Helsinki, Finland | 2002 - 2010

BUSINESS MANAGER

· The company focused on graphic design for mobile devices. Duties included accounting,

- website maintenance, business communication, and negotiations, as well as customer service and support for end users. Customers included such companies as Sony-Ericsson, Benq, and Nokia. · Negotiated sales with business customers, and handled all communications between the
- developer and the customer, ensuring the customer received the exact product that they wanted.

BBA IN BUSINESS INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY (4.66 GPA)

EDUCATION

Laurea University of Applied Sciences | Espoo, Finland | August 2021 - August 2023

· Recently completed my thesis with a grade of 5. Currently attaining work study credits for graduation in June 2024.

Arcada University of Applied Sciences | Helsinki, Finland | August 2015 - September 2016

BBA INTERNATIONAL BUSINESS

BBA INTERNATIONAL BUSINESS AND LOGISTICS